[
  {
    "question": "What is the major weakness in WEP, exploited by the PTW attack used in the lab?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The initialization vector is too short",
      "No protection against message replay",
      "The integrity check value is too short",
      "The IV is part of key stream."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of the WEP initialization vector (IV)?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["24 bits", "32 bits", "48 bits", "64 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are EAP messages transported between the authenticator and the authentication server in RSN?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "EAP messages are encapsulated in TCP/IP",
      "EAP messages are encapsulated in EAP-TLS",
      "EAP messages are encapsulated in VPN",
      "EAP messages are encapsulated in 802.1x"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cryptographic algorithm is used in counter mode with cipher block chaining message authentication code protocol in CCMP?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["AES", "Michael", "RC4", "KASUMI"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the EAPOL 4-way handshake?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "To compute a fresh pairwise temporal key (PTK) from the pairwise message key (PMK)",
      "To compute a fresh pairwise master key (PMK) from the pairwise transient key (PTK)",
      "To compute a fresh pairwise transient key (PTK) from the pairwise master key (PMK) after both parties have verified the PMK",
      "To compute a fresh pairwise message key (PMK) from the pairwise trusted key (PTK) generated in the 4-way key agreement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the counter mode operation of a block cipher E() work?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "\\(C = E(i) \\oplus i\\)",
      "\\(C = E(i) \\oplus M \\oplus i\\)",
      "\\(C_i = E(i)  M_i\\)",
      "\\(C = E(i) \\oplus M\\)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the complete MAC PDU encrypted by the CCMP?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, the CCMP uses a shared key",
      "Yes, the CCMP header is encrypted",
      "No, the MAC header is not encrypted",
      "No, the MAC header and the CCMP header are not encrypted"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which block cipher mode of operation is used for AES in RSN?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Counter Mode with Cipher Block Chaining Message Authentication Code",
      "Counter Mode with Galois Message Authentication Code",
      "Cipher Block Chaining with Counter Mode Message Authentication Code",
      "Cipher Block Chaining with Hashed Message Authentication Code"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the 128 bits start value of the counter for CCMP encryption initialized in RSN?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "By a random IV",
      "By the concatenation of IV and the extended IV",
      "By flag/priority bits, packet number, source-address, and a constant",
      "By source address, destination address and the MIC value of the MPDU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 802.11 frame type is cryptographically protected by the 802.11w standard?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "Data frames",
      "Control frames",
      "Management frames",
      "Beacon frames"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the subscriber identity protected from radio channel eavesdropping in UMTS?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "By the network providing temporary subscriber identities to the USIMs",
      "By keeping the subscriber identity in the USIM only",
      "By storing the 128-bit secret key (\\(K_{IMSI}\\)) in the USIM, and distribute only to trusted VLRs",
      "By using the IMEI instead of the IMSI"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which information is sent from the HSS to the MME during the LTE/EPS authentication protocol?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "IMSI, RAND, AUTN, XRES",
      "RAND, AUTIN, XIRES, \\(K_{ASME}\\)",
      "RAND, AUTN, XRES, CK, IK",
      "RAND, AUTN, XRES, \\(K_c\\)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which UTRAN protocol layers provide encryption?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "MAC layer and RRC layer",
      "RLC layer and RRC layer",
      "PHY layer and MAC layer",
      "MAC layer and RLC layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens if the result of the UTRAN cryptoalgorithm negotiation is that the user equipment (UE) and the network do not have a common encryption algorithm?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "UTRAN provides a new encryption algorithm as an app download",
      "The connection is shut down immediately by UTRAN",
      "UTRAN may establish the connection without encryption",
      "UTRAN does not use encryption algorithm negotiation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which mode of operation is KASUMI used for constructing the 3GPP f8 key stream generator?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Combining Counter-mode and ECB-mode",
      "Combining Counter-mode and CCM-mode",
      "Combining Counter-mode and OFB-mode",
      "Combining Counter-mode and CBC-mode"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the underlying assumption for the MILENAGE security analysis?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "No assumptions were made",
      "The kernel function must be a secure block cipher",
      "AES must be used as the kernel function",
      "The kernel function must be a one-way function"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can the USIM be physically removed from the rest of the UE?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UE manufacturing and lifecycle can be managed independently from the personalization and subscription process",
      "The failure rate of the integrated circuit cards (UICCs) are high because the issuers (mobile operators) want to reduce cost for short subscription duration",
      "End-to-end UMTS key-card may be plugged into the USIM slot for key distribution and management",
      "The USIM holds an expiration date and, like credit cards, must be replaced"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the bit length of the permanent subscriber key in UMTS?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["56", "64", "128", "256"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of the user data encryption in EPS are",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the MME",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The UICC and the MME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of signal-message encryption in the EPS access stratum are",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The eNB and the MME",
      "The UE and the MIME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The end points of signal-message integrity protection in the EPS non-stratum access are",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "The UICC and the eNB",
      "The UE and the eNB",
      "The eNB and the MME",
      "The UE and the MME"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does LTE/EPS provide end-to-end data security?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "Yes, but only authenticity",
      "Yes, but only anonymity",
      "Yes, both confidentiality and authenticity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can a 3G USIM work in an LTE UE handset?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "No, because the cryptokeys must be kept in the USIM",
      "No, because the cryptokeys are not compatible",
      "Yes, because the cryptokeys are the same in the two systems",
      "Yes, because the USIM cryptokey output is the same in the two systems"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the key derivation function KDF of EPS reside?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": "2011 Fall",
    "options": [
      "In the USIM and the AuC",
      "In the USIM and the UE",
      "In the UE and the MME",
      "In the UE and the HSS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is lawful interception in mobile communication networks?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Eavesdropping approved by judicial court",
      "Eavesdropping performed by or on behalf of the police authorities",
      "Signal jamming ordered by the police authorities",
      "Law enforcement command to the mobile operators to turn off the communication encryption in order to enable eavesdropping"
    ]
  }
]
